<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Govind G Nair</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Govind G Nair</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 04 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>A Citizen&#39;s guide to the Economics of a City</title>
      <link>/2020/04/04/a-citizen-s-guide-to-the-economics-of-a-city/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/04/04/a-citizen-s-guide-to-the-economics-of-a-city/</guid>
      <description>The world is rapidly urbanizing. More than half the world lives in urban areas. By 2050, it is projected that close to 7 billion people will live in urban areas in 2050. If you are reading this, you are almost certainly living in a city.
This blog post is in essence a selective synopsis of the fantastic book - Order Without Design — How Markets Shape Cities’ by Alain Bertaud. The book is largely targeted at urban planners and is probably not going to be a NY Times best seller.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to Gaussian Processes</title>
      <link>/2019/08/11/introduction-to-gaussian-processes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/08/11/introduction-to-gaussian-processes/</guid>
      <description>Gaussian DistributionsFundamental to understanding a Gaussian process is a Gaussian distribution.The 1 dimensional version of the Gaussian distribution is the Normal distribution or the Bell Curve.
The plot of a standard normal distribution with mean 0 and variance 1 is shown below. Note that the curve doesn’t look like a perfect bell as the data has been simulated
set.seed(0)plot(density(rnorm(100000)),main = bquote(&amp;quot;N(&amp;quot;~mu~&amp;quot;=0,&amp;quot;~sigma^2~&amp;quot;=1)&amp;quot;))A bi-variate Gaussian distribution is simply a Gaussian distribution in 2 dimensions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R Studio Conference 2019</title>
      <link>/2019/03/17/r-studio-conference-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/03/17/r-studio-conference-2019/</guid>
      <description>This is a notebook summarizing what I learned at the R Studio Conference 2019 Links to all the talks and slide decks,including talks on how to use R in production at scale are available at https://github.com/kbroman/RStudioConf2019Slides
Make sure the libraries being used in each section are installed.
Reproducible Examples with reprexThe reprex package allows you to create a minimal reproducible example that you can share if you are reporting an issue on Github or asking a question on stack overflow.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to Bayesian Methods</title>
      <link>/2019/02/21/introduction-to-bayesian-methods/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/02/21/introduction-to-bayesian-methods/</guid>
      <description>IntroductionThis post will cover the following topics
Differences between Bayesian and Frequentist ApproachesA Simple Bayesian AnalysisSimple Bayesian Linear RegressionBayesianism vs FrequentismIn the simplest terms, in Frequentism parameters are fixed while data can vary.Whereas, in Bayesianism parameters can vary while data is fixed
For frequentists,probability only has meaning in terms of a limiting case of repeated measurements, it is fundamentally related to the frequencies of events.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>